Guide to the John S. Knight Journalism Fellowships at Stanford, Records SC1300
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
John S. Knight Journalism Fellowships at Stanford, Records
1963-2016
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Nelson, Lyle M.
Stanford University. John S. Knight Journalism Fellowships
SC1300
6 Linear Feet (4 cartons)
Content Description
The collection consists of files from John S. Knight Journalism Fellowships Director Lyle Nelson (1969-1985). Also included are Board of Visitors records, which are restricted for 75 years from date of creation.
Biographical / Historical
The John S. Knight Journalism (JSK) Fellowships at Stanford, connected to the School of Humanities and Sciences, offers up to 20 working journalists a paid 10-month fellowship. The journalism fellowships at Stanford started in 1966, and with a grant from the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation in 1984; the program was renamed for John S. Knight.
Conditions Governing Access
Series 2. Board of Visitors Records are restricted for 75 years from date of creation. The materials are otherwise open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Administrative transfer, 2016.
Arrangement
The records are arranged in two series: Series 1. Director's files: Lyle M. Nelson, and Series 2. Board of Visitors Records
Journalism.; Scholarships; Nelson, Lyle M.; Nelson, Lyle M.; Stanford University. John S. Knight Journalism Fellowships; Stanford University. John S. Knight Journalism Fellowships; Nelson, Lyle M.; Nelson, Lyle M.; Stanford University. John S. Knight Journalism Fellowships; Stanford University. John S. Knight Journalism Fellowships; Nelson, Lyle M.; Stanford University. John S. Knight Journalism Fellowships
- Lyle Nelson papers, Series 1
  - Iran, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Iranian Research - Nelson, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - LMN Misc., 1976 Dec (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lyle M. Nelson - Acapulco conference, 1974 Oct 20-27 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Samoa correspondence, 1972-1973, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Samoa trip ARBA representative, 1976 Jul (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sabbatical and Hawaii, 1974 Sep- Dec (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Paris, New Delhi, Bangkok UNESCO/UNDP, 1973 Apr (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mexico trip addresses, etc State department, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Guadalajara trip, 1973 Jul (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Guadalajara, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Guatemala Brazil, 1975 Aug (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Australia trip New Zealand, 1971 Aug (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Earhart Foundation, 1977 Feb (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence #2 Brazilian visit, 1977 Feb 19-26 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Brazilian journalism educators 1 efa 617, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Brazilians visit, 1977 Feb 19-26 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - XV Lyle M. Nelson - misc., 1976 Jan 1 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - XVI Lyle M. Nelson - misc., 1976 Jun 1 - Jul (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Lyle M. Nelson - misc., 1976 Aug - Oct (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Lyle M. Nelson - misc., 1976 Nov (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 20/20, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Communications in the Americas Proceedings, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chandler Professorship, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Lyle M. Nelson, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Hearst Professorship, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Marek - ABC 20/20, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - McClatchy, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Knight - Letters of congrats, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Orchids, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Orchids, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Orchids, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Storke Professorship, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Communications in the Americas Proceedings, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Director search, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - India study communication satellites for education and development rough draft, 1968 Jun 20 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Report and Recommendations, 1963 Mar (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Educational Television: A policy critique and guide for developing countries, 1973 May (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - A Report Visiting Team to study education in American Samoa, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - The first decade of the Fourth Network, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Televisionaries, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Hearst - Professional in Residence, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The Nature Conservancy TNC, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - PJF - General, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - South American Trip, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - South American Trip I, 1972 Nov - 1974 Mar 31 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Venice, Bonn, Brussells Reykjavik, 1973 Oct (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Lyle M. Nelson - speeches, papers, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - National Commission for coping with interdependence, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Board of Foreign scholarships, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Orchids, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Storke Professorship - letters, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - To Be Filed, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - To Be Filed, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - To Be Filed, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - To Be Filed, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - To Be Filed, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - To Be Filed, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - To Be Filed, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Board of Visitors (Restricted for 75 years), Series 2
  - 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1997 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1995 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1994 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1992 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1991 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1990 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 1987 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 1986 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 1985 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 1984 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 1982 (Box 4, Folder 21)